

PHP FULLSTACK · ENGINEER · MANUFACTURING EXPER

Murwillumbah, NSW, Australia

□ (+61) 420581 152 | Secorentinhillion@gmail.com | Accorentinhillion.com | Cocololco | Incorentinhillion.06703b20

Summary.

Found of startup FabLense, an engineer with over ten years experience, turned programmer with a passion for problem-solving through coding. Highly efficient, adaptable and capable of mastering new software and programming languages.

Proficient in Development PHP, Laravel, HTML5/CSS, Javascript, React, RESTAPI, MySQL, SQL, Python, JAVA, C, VBA, Microsoft Office Suite, PowerBI, Solidworks. Autocad and Android Studio.

Skills

Development PHP, Laravel, HTML5/CSS, Javascript, RESTAPI, MySQL, SQL, Python, JAVA, C, VBA

Softwares Microsoft Office Suite, PowerBI, Solidworks, Autocad, Android Studio **Engineering** Product development, project management, lean manufacturing

Languages English, French

Work Experience __

FabLense - Startup in Manufacturing Optimization

Northern Rivers, NSW Australia

Oct. 2022 - Now

FOUNDER

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

• Created a hardware/software solution to gather manufacturing data.

- Built an electronic tracking device using a Raspberry Pi base, custom PCB, custom interface, and firmware in Python.
- Built a web application on Laravel/MySQL, and deployed the application for each new customer on a private or cloud based Linux server.
- Custom web application manages devices, stores and analyses data and enables customised dashboards and tools to view and analyse data.
- Built an android app to manage and install the devices.
- Identifying potential clients and developing strategies to generate leads.
- Engaging with prospective customers to demonstrate product capabilities and benefits.
- · Managing customer relationships and providing ongoing support to ensure satisfaction and product success.

Sicame Australia - Manufacturer of Electrical Connectors

Yatala, QLD Australia

May. 2016 - Sept. 2022

- Built and deployed a web application using native PHP and SQL to:
 - real-time tracking of production labour cost
 - manage production planning (operators, tools, and machines schedules)
 - manage quality control and production planning
 - track work health and safety issues
 - provide a 3D view of stock location
 - assist HR management (daily schedule, leave and training management)
 - enable live monitoring of machines using custom Arduino devices
 - provide controlled document management
- Developed a custom integration between web application and third-party software (Sybiz).
- Redesigned and built assembly lines to minimise labour and optimise production efficiency.
- Redesigned products to reduce material and manufacturing costs.
- Redesigned factory layout to optimise material and product flows.
- Project managed the design, fabrication and on-site installation of new solar farm connectors.

Sicame Australia - Manufacturer of Electrical Connectors

Yatala, QLD Australia

May. 2011 - May. 2016

- Designed, developed and introduced new products for low and medium voltage overhead connectors.
- Tested products to ANSI/IEC/AS Standards (American/European/Australian) in in-house NATA certified laboratory.
- Responsible for design, testing, patent application, industrialisation and customer training of the MechaSplice, an overhead connector patented in the USA
- Monitored and improved procedures to adhere to ISO 9001:2015 and ISO 14001:2015 within the engineering office and test laboratories.
- · Provided remote and on-site customer support and training.

Education

PRODUCT ENGINEER

ICAM, Institut Catholique des Arts et Metiers

Nantes, France

Sep. 2006 - June. 2011

DIPLOME D'INGENIEUR - MASTER DEGREE OF ENGINEERING
• Icam trains generalists/multidisciplinary engineers

SEPTEMBER 12, 2024 CORENTIN HILLION · RÉSUMÉ